# MITCHELL R. DORSEY

5793 Opengate Court, Cincinnati, OH 45247

(513) 203-3344 -- Github: https://github.com/mitchdorsey

Email: mitchellrdorsey@gmail.com -- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mitchelldorsey/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Junior developer searching for a role that allows me to use my adaptability and communication skills. Constantly broadening my skill set both technically and mentally. Past work experiences have given me strengths in thinking on my feet and continuously being flexible. Programmer that enjoys collaborating with a resourceful team.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Object Oriented Programming: C#, .NET, .NET Core, ASP.NET Web Forms, Java (Android framework)

**Web Application Development:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MVC, Bootstrap, XML (Android framework), Python **Database Programming:** SQL, table design and creation

**Development tools and techniques:** Entity Framework, Agile, Git, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SSMS, MySQL Workbench, Android Studio, unit testing (MS Unit), integration testing, TDD, command line navigation

# **EDUCATION**

Tech Elevator - Cincinnati, Ohio

September 2018 - December 2018

14-week .NET coding bootcamp learning database programming, .NET frameworks and design patterns, web application security, server side programming and client side web programming

## **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

Family Reading Tracker --- http://familyreadingtracker.apphb.com/

• Web app developed in C#/.Net using MVC pattern, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript

### **Stock Market App**

Web app developed in C#/. Net Core using MVC pattern, consumes Stock Market Web API, Javascript

# American Football Score Keeper --- Android mobile app

Developed in Java and XML allowing the user to keep track of the score between 2 teams

#### Coffee Purchase --- Android mobile app

• Developed in Java and XML simulating a coffee transaction that integrates an Email Intent

#### Book Listing App --- Android mobile app

Developed in Java and XML, lists the published books on a given topic using the Google Books API

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Physna - Cincinnati, Ohio

February 2019 - December 2019

# Junior Software Developer

- Implemented features on object-oriented web app with MySQL database and desktop client app
- Coordinated with Application Engineer to evaluate and improve software
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches
- Built desktop client installer file used for distribution

**Lynch Imports** - Sunman, Indiana

April 2014 - August 2018

#### **Inventory Specialist**

- Received recognition by name from multiple customers regarding workplace positivity and valuing customers' time
- Continuously learned a variety of new technical and mechanical skills
- Applied practical reasoning and critical thinking with team members to determine course of action for inventory consolidation across many storage locations
- Factored numerous industry regulations into decision making on a daily basis